Let's look at Na2O.
Na2O is going to
go 2Na+ plus O2-.
How about alumina?
That's on there, Al2O3.
Well, that's going to
go to 2Al3+ plus 3O2-.
Notice a pattern.
The pattern is you get O2-.
We can understand
why O2- minus has
been used, why
chemistry has been
used to change the properties
of glass for millennia.
And the reason goes
back to the pictures
that we drew on Monday
where we started
by talking about the chemistry
of the silicate group.
So remember Si?
Remember this?
An SiO4 is happy if it's
got four minus charges.
Remember that?
We started with Lewis and
it satisfies the octet.
But then in glass what
happens is you bridge.
And so you have this.
And I won't draw all of them.
I'll just draw it the
way we drew it before.
And you have these bridges,
and all of these oxygens
are bridges in glass.